?Are you ready, kids-
？你们准​​备好了吗，孩子们——
.KIDS: Aye aye, captain
.KIDS：是啊，队长
.I can't hear you-
.我听不到你说话-
.KIDS: Aye aye, captain
.KIDS：是啊，队长
THEME SONG: Oh, who lives in
?a pineapple under the sea
主题曲：哦，谁住在
？海底的菠萝
.SpongeBob SquarePants
.海绵宝宝
,Absorbent, and yellow
.and porous is he
,吸水性,黄色
.他是多孔的
.SpongeBob SquarePants
.海绵宝宝
If nautical nonsense
.be something you wish
如果航海废话
.成为你想要的东西
.SpongeBob SquarePants
.海绵宝宝
Then drop on the deck
.and flop like a fish
然后落在甲板上
.然后像鱼一样扑通扑通
.SpongeBob SquarePants
.海绵宝宝
?Ready
？准备好
.SpongeBob SquarePants
.海绵宝宝
[LAUGHTER]
[笑声]
[BUBBLING]
[冒泡]
,MR. KRABS: Come on
.SpongeBob, it's quitting time
，先生。蟹蟹：来吧
海绵宝宝，该下班了
[CLICK]
[点击]
.I've got a card game tonight
.今晚我要玩纸牌游戏
Who you playing-
?cards with, Mr. Krabs
你在扮演谁——
?与蟹老板先生打牌
I'm going over to the Chum-
.Bucket to play with Plankton
我要去密友那里-
.与浮游生物一起玩的桶
[GASP]
[喘气]
?Plankton-
?浮游生物-
But Mr. Krabs, he's
.your arch-enemy
但蟹老板先生，他是
.你的宿敌
He's been trying to steal the
.Krabby Patty formula for years
他一直试图偷窃
.Krabby Patty 配方多年
[SMACK]
[咂]
.Ouch-
。哎哟-
Why would you play-
?cards with him
你为什么要玩——
？和他一起打卡
,Between you and me-
Plankton is the worst
,你我之间——
浮游生物是最糟糕的
.card player in Bikini Bottom
比基尼泳裤中的 .card 玩家
Why, I've been taking him to the
cleaners every Thursday night
为什么，我一直带他去
每周四晚上清洁工
.for 15 years
.15年
.I never lose
.我从不输
[LAUGHTER]
[笑声]
[SOBBING]
[抽泣]
[LAUGHTER]
[笑声]
Taking him to the-
.cleaners, that's a hot one
带他去——
.cleaners，这是一个热门的
How'd the card game go
.last night, Mr. Krabs
卡牌游戏进行得怎么样
.昨晚，蟹老板
.I lost-
.我输了-
.Barnacles, Mr. Krabs-
.藤壶，蟹老板-
?How much money did you lose
?你损失了多少钱
.I didn't lose any money-
.我没有损失任何钱-
--I lost
——我输了
Don't tell me you-
.lost the Krusty Krab
别告诉我你-
.失去了蟹堡王
--I lost-
——我输了——
Mr. Krabs, please-
tell me you didn't
螃蟹先生，请——
告诉我你没有
lose the Krabby
.Patty secret formula
失去蟹蟹
.帕蒂秘密配方
!I lost you-
！我失去了你——
?What-
？什么-
I bet your-
.contract, and I lost
我敢打赌你的——
.合同，我输了
[LAUGHING]
[笑]
.Good one, Mr. Krabs-
.好样的，蟹老板-
Well, I got to go make
.those Krabby Patties
好吧，我得走了
.那些蟹肉饼
.Ugh
。啊
.MUMBLING] D'oh]
.咕哝]D'oh]
I'm afraid you don't-
.work here anymore
恐怕你不会——
.不再在这里工作了
Please tell me-
.this isn't a joke
请告诉我-
.这不是玩笑
.Go on, Mr. Krabs-
.继续吧，蟹老板-
.Tell him
.告诉他
Tell him all about
.your cruel, sick joke
告诉他一切
.你的残酷、恶心的笑话
As much as I love-
,cruel, sick jokes
尽我所爱——
,残酷的,病态的笑话
.I'm afraid he's not joking
.恐怕他不是在开玩笑
.You work for me now, SpongeBob
.你现在为我工作了，海绵宝宝
Time to put on the official
.Chum Bucket bucket helmet
是时候穿上官方的衣服了
.Chum Bucket 水桶头盔
[CLANG]
[铛]
[SCREAMS]
[尖叫声]
But Mr. Krabs, I don't-
.want to work for him
但是蟹老板，我不-
.想为他工作
I want to work for you
.here at the Krusty Krab
我想为你工作
.在蟹堡王这里
[SOBBING]
[抽泣]
.I'm sorry, boy-
.我很抱歉，男孩-
[SOBBING]
[抽泣]
.It's all my fault
.都是我的错
,What kind of cold-
heartless person
,什么样的冷-
无情的人
would break apart such
?a loving relationship
会分解这样的
? 一段充满爱的关系
!SINGING) I would)
！唱歌）我愿意）
!Ah-
！啊-
!SpongeBob-
！海绵宝宝-
!Mr. Krabs-
！先生。蟹蟹-
[CLANG]
[铛]
[CLINK]
[碰杯]
This is your greatest-
.blunder, Krabs
这是你最伟大的——
.错误，蟹蟹
For 15 years, I've been
,throwing those card games
15年来，我一直
，扔那些纸牌游戏
.just waiting for you to slip up
.只等你犯错
I may not have the precious
,Krabby Patty formula
我可能没有珍贵的
,蟹黄饼配方
but I got the next best
.thing-- the guy who makes them
但我得到了下一个最好的
.thing——制造它们的人
I'm going to run you
.out of business, Krabs
我要追你
.停业了，蟹老板
!Mr. Krabs-
！先生。蟹蟹-
!SpongeBob-
！海绵宝宝-
[CRYING]
[哭泣]
?Can I have my arms back
？我可以收回我的手臂吗
[BUBBLING]
[冒泡]
?I-- what is this place-
？我——这是什么地方——
[MECHANICAL NOISES]
[机械噪音]
!Ah-
！啊-
[BUZZING]
[嗡嗡声]
!Oh, no-
！哦，不——
[SLAM]
OK, I'm ready for-
.my Krabby Patty
好的，我准备好了——
.我的克拉比帕蒂
,Actually, Mr. Plankton-
--sir, I haven't, uh
，实际上，浮游生物先生——
——先生，我没有，呃
.Perhaps you don't understand-
.也许你不明白-
.You work for me now
.你现在为我工作
And as your new
boss, I command you
而作为你的新
老大，我命令你
to make me a patty
this instant, or I'll
给我做一块肉饼
就在这一刻，不然我就
be forced to remove your
brain and implant it
被迫删除你的
大脑并植入它
.in my robot chef
.在我的机器人厨师里
[CHUGGING]
[嘎嘎声]
.So get cooking
.所以开始做饭吧
[SPRING]
[春天]
[BLAST]
[爆炸]
[BEEPING]
[嘟嘟声]
,The sign says kitchen-
.but my heart says gaol
,标牌上写着厨房-
.但我的心说监狱
SINGING) A stove is a stove)
.no matter where you go
唱歌）炉子就是炉子）
.无论你去哪里
.SINGING) A patty is a patty)-
.唱歌）小馅饼就是小馅饼）-
.That's what I say
.这就是我说的
.SINGING) A grill is a grill)-
.唱歌）烤架就是烤架）-
.This is surely so
.确实如此
SINGING) And fries)-
.should be fries either way
唱歌）还有薯条）-
.无论如何都应该是薯条
SINGING) But this)-
.grill is not a home
唱歌）但是这个）-
.grill 不是一个家
.This is not the stove I know
.这不是我认识的炉子
SINGING) I would)-
trade it all away
唱歌）我愿意）-
全部交易掉
.if you'd come back to stay
.如果你愿意回来留下来
MR. KRABS AND
(SPONGEBOB: (SINGING
先生。蟹和
（海绵宝宝：（唱歌
This kitchen's not
.the same without you
这个厨房不是
.没有你也一样
SINGING) It's)-
.just a greasy spoon
唱歌）是）-
.只是一个油腻的勺子
SINGING) Just a greasy spoon)-
唱歌）只是一把油腻的勺子）-
:MR. KRABS AND SPONGEBOB
.SINGING) Without you)
：先生。螃蟹和海绵宝宝
.唱歌）没有你）
[SOBBING]
[抽泣]
?What is he doing-
？他在做什么-
?All these tears
？所有这些眼泪
?And the show tunes
？以及演出曲调
?Why isn't he making the patties
？他为什么不做馅饼
.Forget it
。忘了它
I'm going with plan B. I'll put
.his brain in the robot chef
我将采用 B 计划。我会把
.他的大脑在机器人厨师里
[CHUGGING]
[嘎嘎声]
COMPUTER: You know
.that never works
电脑：你知道
.那永远行不通
.The answer is obvious
.答案是显而易见的
To get to the
SpongeBob, you must
为了到达
海绵宝宝，你必须
show him compassion
.and understanding
向他表示同情心
.和理解
Then he'll give
.you what you want
然后他会给
.你想要什么
?Will you be quiet-
？你能安静点吗-
.I'm thinking
.我在想
.I've got it
.我明白了
To get to the
SpongeBob, I'll show
为了到达
海绵宝宝，我来展示
him compassion
.and understanding
他同情
.和理解
.Then he'll give me what I want
.然后他会给我我想要的
[BUBBLING]
[冒泡]
[ZAPPING]
[切换]
[GRUMBLING]
[抱怨]
.Hey-
。嘿-
!Ah-
！啊-
.I'm sorry, Plankton
.对不起，浮游生物
.I'm trying my best
.我正在尽力
I'm not used to
.cooking this way
我不习惯
.这样煮
.Please don't take my brain out
.请不要把我的大脑取出来
.Hold it, SpongeBob-
.坚持住，海绵宝宝-
I'm capable of compassion
.and understanding
我有能力慈悲
.和理解
?Really-
？真的-
Then I'd like to go
.back to the Krusty Krab
那我想去
.回到蟹堡王
.Let's not get carried away-
.我们不要得意忘形-
Now what can I do
to make you more
现在我能做什么
让你更
comfortable here
.at the Chum Bucket
这里很舒服
.在密友桶里
Well, I usually-
.cook on a grill
嗯，我通常——
.在烤架上做饭
!You got it-
！你明白了-
[BUBBLING]
[冒泡]
[GRUNTS]
[咕噜声]
Well, it wasn't easy, but here
.it is-- one old frying grill
嗯，这并不容易，但是在这里
.它是——一个旧的煎烤架
?How about we try it out
？我们试试怎么样
Uh, it's just that I'm used-
.to the grill facing that way
呃，只是我习惯了-
.到面向那个方向的烤架
.Say no more-
.不多说了-
.I'll take care of everything
.我会处理好一切
[GRUNTING]
[咕噜声]
?How about here
?这里怎么样
.A little more to the left-
.再往左边一点-
[GRUNTING]
[咕噜声]
?How's this, SpongeBob-
？怎么样，海绵宝宝-
.Move it over a little more-
.再移动一点-
[GRUNTING]
[咕噜声]
?Here-
？这里-
.Keep going-
。继续前进-
[GRUNTING]
[咕噜声]
?Here-
？这里-
.Almost-
。几乎-
.That's it
。就是这样
.Just a little more
.再多一点
[GRUNTING]
[咕噜声]
!Perfect-
！完美的-
.Right there
.就在那里
[GROWLING]
[咆哮]
.I don't know
。我不知道
Something still
.doesn't feel right
仍然有一些东西
.感觉不对
[BUBBLING]
[冒泡]
PLANKTON: Just a few
.more steps, SpongeBob
浮游生物：只有一些
.更多步骤，海绵宝宝
.OK
。好的
.Go ahead
。前进
.Take it off
.脱下来
It's an exact replica of
.the Krusty Krab kitchen
这是一个精确的复制品
.蟹堡王厨房
.Oh, it is an exact replica-
.哦，这是一个精确的复制品-
,Here's the sink
,the greasy fryers
,这是水槽
,油腻的油炸锅
--the squeaky floorboards
——吱吱作响的地板
[SQUEAKING]
[吱吱声]
.and that thing--
.还有那个东西--
One Krabby Patty
.coming up, Mr. Krabs
一份蟹肉饼
.即将到来，蟹老板先生
[SOBBING]
[抽泣]
.Oh, Mr. Krabs
.哦，蟹老板
.Don't cry, SpongeBob-
.别哭，海绵宝宝-
I'll show you it's much
.better working for me
我会告诉你这有很多
.更好地为我工作
Is there anything
that old skinflint
有什么吗
那个老顽皮的人
?Krabs wouldn't let you have
？螃蟹不会让你拥有
Well, there is one-
.thing I've always wanted
嗯，有一个——
.我一直想要的东西
[BUBBLING]
[冒泡]
.Wow-
。哇-
So now do you-
have everything you
那么现在你-
拥有你的一切
need to make some
?Krabby Patties
需要做一些
?蟹肉饼
--Well-
- 出色地-
?You ready to make some patties-
？你准备好做一些馅饼了-
Wait until I-
.finish my ice cream
等到我——
.吃完我的冰淇淋
?How about those patties-
？那些肉饼怎么样-
!Ah-
！啊-
!Faster
！快点
[BUBBLING]
[冒泡]
And then the littlest-
.sea elf said-- oof
然后是最小的——
.海精灵说——噢
?Huh
？哈
[SNORING]
[打鼾]
!You
！你
[GROWLING]
[咆哮]
.Steady, Plankton
.稳定，浮游生物
It's all going to
.pay off soon enough
一切都会过去
.尽快还清
[CRASH]
[碰撞]
.Hey there, sleepyhead
.嘿，瞌睡虫
?What do you say
？你怎么说
All the preparation-
.is making me hungry
一切准备工作——
.让我饿了
.Me too-
。我也是-
You know what would
?really hit the spot
你知道会发生什么
?真的恰到好处
Why don't you whip us up a
.couple of Krabby Patties
你为什么不鞭策我们
.几块蟹肉饼
.Mm-
。毫米-
I'm kind of in the
.mood for tacos
我有点像在
.心情炸玉米饼
.Ha, ha-
.哈哈哈哈-
.Good one, SpongeBob
.好样的，海绵宝宝
But really, why don't you go
?ahead and make us a patty
但说实话，你为什么不走呢？
？继续给我们做肉饼
[YAWNS]
[哈欠]
.No-
。不-
.I don't really feel like it
.我真的不喜欢这样
.But I don't understand-
.但我不明白-
You have the grill, and the
.spatula, and the comfy chair
你有烤架，还有
.spatula，和舒适的椅子
.I rubbed your putrid feet
.我揉了揉你腐烂的脚
,Tell you what, half pint-
?why don't you ask me later
，告诉你什么，半品脱-
？你为什么不稍后问我
.Grr-
.咕噜-
I command you to make
!me a patty this instant
我命令你做
！我现在就是一块肉饼
!No-
！不-
!Don't back sass me-
！别回骂我-
.Blah, blah, blah, blah-
.巴拉，巴拉，巴拉，巴拉-
?What-
？什么-
[RAZZES]
[拉兹]
.That's it, mister-
.就是这样，先生-
You just lost your
.brain privileges
你刚刚失去了你的
.大脑特权
[BUBBLING]
[冒泡]
[ZAPPING]
[切换]
!Finished-
！完成的-
.SpongeBob, come in here
.海绵宝宝，进来吧
Or should I say RobotBob
?SpongeShiftPants
或者我应该说机器人鲍勃
?海绵移位裤
I put the brain in
?the robot, you know
我把大脑放进去
？机器人，你知道吗
You shouldn't have
.been a spoiled brat
你不应该有
.曾经是个被宠坏的孩子
You see, I always
.get what I want
你看，我总是
.得到我想要的
And I want you to make
.me a Krabby Patty
我希望你能做到
.me 蟹肉饼
[BEEPING]
[嘟嘟声]
Beep, beep, doo-
.ba deep deep do
嘟嘟嘟——
.ba深深做
Response-- why don't
?you ask me later
回应——为什么不呢
？你稍后问我
?What-
？什么-
!What
！什么
.Get welded-
.焊接-
.Wait I command you-
.等等我命令你-
.Make me a Krabby Patty
.给我做一份蟹肉饼
.I don't wanna-
.我不想-
[SLURP]
[咕噜咕噜]
!Ah-
！啊-
Well, old girl, this looks-
.like our final chapter
好吧，老姑娘，这看起来——
.就像我们的最后一章
!Oh
！哦
SNIVELLING) I)-
.can't take anymore
抽泣）我）-
.不能再忍受了
You've got to take that
.yellow nightmare back
你必须接受这个
.黄色噩梦回来了
.It's not worth it
.这不值得
I'm better off stealing a
.Krabby Patty fair and square
我最好偷一个
.Krabby Patty 光明正大
Um, well, a deal's-
.a deal, Plankton
嗯，好吧，一笔交易——
.一笔交易，浮游生物
.He's your headache now
.他现在是你的头疼事
!Oh, please-
！哦，拜托-
!Have mercy, Krabs
！发发慈悲吧，蟹蟹们
.I'll do anything
.我会做任何事
.I beg of you
.我求你了
How about you give me $50, and-
.I'll take him off your hands
你给我 50 美元怎么样，然后——
.我会把他从你手中夺走
!It's a deal-
！这是一笔交易——
.I cheated anyway
.反正我作弊了
Now be gone with-
.you, you puny pest
现在就走吧-
.你，你这个微不足道的害虫
.Thank you-
。谢谢-
[CRASH]
[碰撞]
.Ouch
。哎哟
My brain and I are glad-
.to be back, Mr. Krabs
我的大脑和我很高兴-
.回来吧，蟹老板
.Glad to have you back, lad-
.很高兴你回来了，小伙子-
.Now, get to those patties
.现在，吃那些馅饼
.The lunch rush is a coming
.午餐高峰即将到来
.Ah-
。啊-
.I don't feel like it
.我不喜欢这样
Why don't you ask
?me later, Krabby
你为什么不问
？稍后我，克拉比
[LAUGHTER]
[笑声]
I mean, I'm working all
.day for free, my treat
我的意思是，我正在努力工作
.一天免费，我请客
MR. KRABS: That's what
.I thought you said
先生。蟹蟹：就是这样
.我以为你说
[MUSIC PLAYING]
[音乐播放]
[BUBBLING]
[冒泡]
.NARRATOR: Well, well
.旁白：好吧，好吧
?What is this
?这是什么
.Ah, the artist at sea
.啊，海上的艺术家
Let us watch and see the
.fruits of his struggle
让我们拭目以待
.他奋斗的成果
[DING]
[叮]
Oh it seems as if
.inspiration has struck
哦，好像
.灵感袭来
[KISS]
[吻]
[MUMBLING]
[咕哝]
.Oop-
.哎呀-
.My pencil
.我的铅笔
?What
？什么
.Oh
。哦
NARRATOR: The artist has learned
--the first lesson of the sea
旁白：艺术家已经学会了
——大海的第一堂课
.always being a spare pencil
.永远是一支备用铅笔
!No-
！不-
.OK-
。好的-
?Ready, Patrick
？准备好了，帕特里克
.One
。一
.Two-
。二-
.PATRICK AND SPONGEBOB: Three
.帕特里克和海绵宝宝：三
[BLOWING]
[吹]
.Scissors beats paper, Patrick-
.剪刀胜布，帕特里克-
[LAUGHTER]
[笑声]
One-
一-
.PATRICK AND SPONGEBOB: Two
.帕特里克和海绵宝宝：两个
.Three-
。三-
[BLOWING]
[吹]
Patrick, how come
?you always do paper
帕特里克，怎么会这样
？你总是做纸
[POP]
[流行音乐]
[CRASH]
[碰撞]
[SCREAMING]
[尖叫]
?What is that thing, SpongeBob-
？那是什么东西，海绵宝宝-
.It looks like a giant pencil-
.它看起来像一支巨大的铅笔-
.Go touch it-
.去触摸它吧-
.It is a giant pencil, Patrick-
.这是一支巨大的铅笔，帕特里克-
Let's draw some giant
.pictures with it
让我们画一些巨人
.与它的图片
?What you drawing-
？你画什么-
.Stand back, Patrick-
.退后一步，帕特里克-
I can't draw with you
.breathing down my neck
我不能和你一起画画
.沿着我的脖子呼吸
.Pfft-
.噗——
.Artists
.艺术家
.It's a jellyfish-
.这是一只水母-
.Pretty good, SpongeBob-
.很好，海绵宝宝-
But it's lacking
.basic construction
但还欠缺
.基本构造
And your perspective
.leaves a lot to be desired
以及你的观点
.还有很多不足之处
,SPONGEBOB: Eh
.everybody's a critic
,海绵宝宝：呃
.每个人都是批评家
[SLURPING]
[啜饮]
SpongeBob, your-
.drawing's coming to life
海绵宝宝，你的——
.绘画变得栩栩如生
Ha, ha, that's more-
.like it, Mr. Critic
哈哈哈哈，还有这个
.喜欢它，评论家先生
!No-
！不-
.I mean it's swimming away
.我的意思是它正在游走
Do you know what-
?this means, Patrick
你知道吗-
？这意味着，帕特里克
Your art can never-
.hang in a museum
你的艺术永远不能——
.挂在博物馆里
It means we found-
.a magic pencil
这意味着我们发现——
.一支神奇的铅笔
Now all I need is-
a magic moustache
现在我需要的是——
神奇的小胡子
and all my dreams
.will have come true
和我所有的梦想
.将会实现
.Ha, ha, ha-
.哈哈哈哈-
.Coming right up
.即将到来
!Life is good-
！生活是美好的——
[POP]
[流行音乐]
[FLUTTER]
[扑]
.Easy come, easy go-
。来得便当去得快-
,SQUIDWARD: Squidward
,if you had some hair
,SQUIDWARD: 章鱼哥
，如果你有一些头发
you'd be the most gorgeous
.creature in the sea
你会是最华丽的
.海中的生物
.You've got looks, talent
.你有颜值，有才华
All you need is a
!full head of-- hair
您所需要的只是一个
!满头——头发
.My turn-
.轮到我了-
.Be careful, Patrick-
.小心点，帕特里克-
Being an artist is a
.heavy responsibility
成为一名艺术家是一个
.责任重大
Each work of art is like a child
.and must be treated as such
每一件艺术品都像一个孩子
.并且必须如此对待
.Come on-
。快点-
I was just going
.to draw a cartoon
我正要去
.画卡通
.OK-
。好的-
?Why didn't you say so
？你为什么不这么说
.Hey, another jellyfish-
.嘿，另一只水母-
.It's Squidward, silly-
.这是章鱼哥，傻瓜-
[MUMBLING]-
[咕哝]-
Kind of creepy-
.looking when it moves
有点令人毛骨悚然——
.看它何时移动
.You're right, SpongeBob-
.你是对的，海绵宝宝-
.We can't let him go into town-
.我们不能让他进城-
[MUMBLING]
[咕哝]
.Poor Squidward-
.可怜的章鱼哥-
[DING]
[叮]
Hey, my brain just-
.hatched an idea
嘿，我的大脑只是——
.萌生了一个想法
[LAUGHTER]
[笑声]
.This is going to be classic
.这将成为经典
I think I fancy a-
.stroll around the park
我想我喜欢一个——
.在公园里漫步
[DOORBELL]
[门铃]
?SPONGEBOB: Oh, Squidward
海绵宝宝：哦，章鱼哥
?What do you want-
？你想要什么-
?Hello
？你好
?What's this
?这是什么
Someone left me some
.money for a perm
有人给我留了一些
.烫发的钱
[LAUGHTER]
[笑声]
.Come to Harry
.来到哈利身边
!Ow
！噢
[LAUGHTER]
[笑声]
!SpongeBob-
！海绵宝宝-
!Oh, my hair
！哦，我的头发
!SpongeBob
!海绵宝宝
[SLAM]
[LAUGHTER]
[笑声]
.Wait-
。等待-
.I've got another idea
.我有另一个想法
.This will be the ultimate prank
.这将是终极恶作剧
.I'll draw me
.我来画我
And when Squidward answers
.the door, it won't be me
当章鱼哥回答时
.门，不会是我
[LAUGHTER]
[笑声]
.Aw, look at him
.噢，看看他
?Ain't he a doll
？他不是一个洋娃娃吗？
.All he needs is a tie
.他所需要的只是一条领带
.Ready for action
.准备行动
[MUMBLING]
[咕哝]
[LAUGHTER]
[笑声]
.PATRICK: He's going to the door
.PATRICK：他要去门口了
[GIGGLING]
[咯咯笑]
[KNOCKING]
[敲门声]
.He's knocking at the door-
.他在敲门-
[DOOR OPENS]
[门打开]
Squidward's answering
--the door and
章鱼哥的回答
——门和
!Oh-
！哦-
!Ow
！噢
!Ow, ow, ow
！ 噢，噢，噢
.He's beating up Squidward-
.他正在殴打章鱼哥-
.Ha, ha, ha
.哈哈哈
!Ow-
！噢-
!Ouch
！哎哟
.Ow, ow, ow, ow
.呜呜呜
!DoodleBoy, stop-
！DoodleBoy，停下——
!Ow-
！噢-
[CRASH]
[碰撞]
.Ow
.噢
[MUMBLING]
[咕哝]
.Ugh-
。啊-
[MUMBLING]
[咕哝]
.He's got the pencil
.他有铅笔
?What have I done-
？我做了什么-
.We've got to find him
.我们必须找到他
[BUBBLING]
[冒泡]
?Where could he possibly be
？他可能在哪里
Maybe he's in that-
.poorly drawn pineapple
或许他就在那个——
.画得不好的菠萝
.Come on-
。快点-
.Let's go
。我们走吧
.I'm not going in there-
.我不会进去-
.Come on, Patrick-
.来吧，帕特里克-
.I'm right behind you
.我就在你身后
.Baby steps
.婴儿学步
.Almost there
.快到了
[SCREAMS]
[尖叫声]
[THUD]
[轰鸣声]
.What just happened-
.刚刚发生了什么-
[MUMBLING]
[咕哝]
.Come on, Patrick-
.来吧，帕特里克-
.Give me a boost up
.给我动力
Can't we just stay down-
?here where it's safe
我们不能就这样呆下去吗-
？这里是安全的地方
.No way-
。决不-
,I created this monster
.and I've got to stop him
,我创造了这个怪物
.我必须阻止他
.Oof-
。钱币-
[MUMBLING]
[咕哝]
?See what I mean, Patrick-
？明白我的意思，帕特里克-
?Where's the leak, ma'am-
？泄漏在哪里，女士-
[SCREAM]
[尖叫]
[CRASH]
[碰撞]
?You OK, Patrick-
？你还好吧，帕特里克-
!PATRICK: Finland
！帕特里克：芬兰
[MUMBLING]
[咕哝]
[BUBBLING]
[冒泡]
[MUMBLING]
[咕哝]
.There he is-
.他在那里——
.He's hideous-
.他很丑-
He makes me sick
.just looking at him
他让我恶心
.只是看着他
,Those big, bulgy eyes
,that square body
,那双凸出的大眼睛
,那个方体
,those two buck teeth
!and that stupid tie
,那两颗龅牙
！还有那条愚蠢的领带
.Uh, ahem-
.呃，咳咳-
Oh, but it looks good-
.on you, SpongeBob
哦，不过看起来不错-
.关于你，海绵宝宝
.Ha, ha
.哈哈
[MUMBLING]
[咕哝]
.He's putting down the pencil-
.他正在放下铅笔-
.This is our chance
.这是我们的机会
On the count of three, we'll
.jump out and surprise him
数到三后，我们
.跳出来给他一个惊喜
!Oh, boy-
！哦，男孩-
.A surprise party
.惊喜派对
?Is it his birthday
？今天是他的生日吗
[CRASH]
[碰撞]
[MUMBLING]
[咕哝]
!Patrick-
！帕特里克-
!Patrick
！帕特里克
!Do something
！做点什么
!Happy birthday-
！生日快乐-
Ah-
啊-
.Here's your present-
.这是你的礼物-
[THUNK]
[咚]
.You're welcome
。不客气
[MUMBLING]
[咕哝]
.Hold it right there, Doodle-
.就在那里，Doodle-
I brought you into
this world, and now I'm
我带你进入
这个世界，现在我
.going to take you out
.要带你出去
?Any last words
？还有什么遗言吗？
[MUMBLING]
[咕哝]
.I, I'm sorry-
.我，对不起-
?What was that
？那是什么？
[MUMBLING SLOWLY]
[缓慢地咕哝]
[SQUEAKING]
[吱吱声]
[MOANING]
[呻吟]
[CRASH]
[碰撞]
.Hold still, Doodle-
.别动，嘟嘟-
.This is for your own good
.这是为了你好
.Take that
.拿那个
.And this
.还有这个
.And that
.还有那个
.And this
.还有这个
.This
。这
.That
。那
.This
。这
.That
。那
[GRUNTING]
[咕噜声]
[SCREAMS]
[尖叫声]
,I am SpongeBob
!destroyer of evil
,我是海绵宝宝
！邪恶的毁灭者
.Take it easy-
。别紧张-
.It's just a drawing
.这只是一张图
Well, that takes care-
?of that, eh, Patrick
嗯，那要小心了——
？那个，呃，帕特里克
.Done and done-
.完成了-
[SQUEAKING]
[吱吱声]
[BUBBLING]
[冒泡]
Gee, Gary, you should-
.have been there
哎呀，加里，你应该——
.去过那里
.It sure was exciting
.这确实令人兴奋
But you know, I kind of
.miss the little Doodle
但你知道，我有点
.怀念小涂鸦
.He was like a son to me
.他对我来说就像一个儿子
But I am glad that things
.are back to normal
但我很高兴事情
.恢复正常
.Well, good night, sweet prince
.好吧，晚安，可爱的王子
.Meow-
.喵-
.Good night magic pencil-
.晚安魔笔-
[SNORING]
[打鼾]
[DOOR OPENS]
[门打开]
[CLICK]
[点击]
[TOILET FLUSHES]
[马桶冲水]
[SNORING]
[打鼾]
[DOOR OPENS]
[门打开]
[SCRIBBLING]
[乱写]
.Oh, hey magic pencil-
.哦，嘿魔法铅笔-
?What are you doing up
?你在做什么
Drawing yourself
?a glass of water
画自己
？一杯水
[LAUGHTER]
[笑声]
!Ah
！啊
!DoodleBob
!涂鸦鲍勃
?No hard feelings, right
？没有难受的感觉，对吧
[SCRIBBLING]
[乱写]
[SCREAMS]
[尖叫声]
What do you think
?you're doing, Doodle
你觉得怎么样
？你在做什么，涂鸦
.You Doodle-
.你涂鸦-
.Me SpongeBob
.我海绵宝宝
[SCREAM]
[尖叫]
[RIP]
[安息吧]
[SCREAMS]
[尖叫声]
[CRASH]
[碰撞]
[SCREAM]
[尖叫]
[MUMBLING]
[咕哝]
[SQUEAKING]
[吱吱声]
?Huh-
？哈-
[SQUEAKING]
[吱吱声]
[MUMBLING]
[咕哝]
[SCREAM]
[尖叫]
.Be careful with that thing-
.小心那个东西-
.Who knows what will happen
.谁知道会发生什么
.I nose
.我鼻子
[MUMBLING]
[咕哝]
[LAUGHTER]
[笑声]
.Very funny, Doodle-
.非常有趣，涂鸦-
.Now it's my turn
.现在轮到我了
[GRUNTING]
[咕噜声]
[SNAP]
[折断]
[SCRIBBLING]
[乱写]
.Well, Doodle
.嗯，涂鸦
.It looks like this is a draw
.看起来这是平局
[PING]
[平]
[BUZZING]
[嗡嗡声]
[PING]
[平]
.You've made your point
.你已经表达了你的观点
.No matter
。不管
I was voted most
.artistic in high school
我得票最多
.高中艺术
[SMASH]
[粉碎]
.SQUIDWARD: Ouch
.SQUIDWARD：哎哟
SpongeBob, you're
.going to pay for that
海绵宝宝，你是
.将为此付出代价
.Uh, maybe it was most clumsy-
.呃，也许这是最笨拙的-
[SCREAMS]
[尖叫声]
[MUMBLING]
[咕哝]
[CHIMES]
[编钟]
?Huh-
？哈-
[MUMBLING]
[咕哝]
?Huh-
？哈-
.Paper
。纸
.Page for Mr. Doodle
.涂鸦先生的页面
[SMACK]
[咂]
[CHIMES]
[编钟]
,PATRICK: Hey, SpongeBob
?what's with all the ruckus
帕特里克：嘿，海绵宝宝
？到底是怎么回事？
Take a look for-
.yourself, Patrick
看看——
.你自己，帕特里克
[GASP]
[喘气]
.It's the evil Doodle-
.这是邪恶的涂鸦-
.No, no-
.不，不-
.Not evil
.不邪恶
He was just a
two-dimensional creature
他只是一个
二维生物
lost in our three-dimensional
,aquatic world
迷失在我们的三维空间中
、水上世界
.longing for a purpose
.渴望一个目标
?So he's a drawing-
？所以他是一幅画-
.Exactly-
。确切地-
?See how happy he is
？看他多高兴
.He still looks kind of creepy-
.他看起来还是有点令人毛骨悚然-
[BUBBLING]
[冒泡]
Oh, great magic-
pencil, your powers
噢，伟大的魔法——
铅笔，你的力量
are too mighty for
,us ocean-dwellers
太强大了
,美国海洋居民
so I will send you back
to the magic kingdom
所以我会把你送回来
前往魔法王国
.from where you came
.从你来的地方
?Are you already, Patrick
？你已经了吗，帕特里克
.Ready-
。准备好-
[BOUNCE]
[弹跳]
--NARRATOR: We rejoin the artist
--旁白：我们重新加入艺术家的行列
[SNORE]
[鼾]
.in a creative slump--
.在创意低潮中--
[SPLASH]
[溅]
?ARTIST: Huh
？艺术家：嗯
?What's, what's this
?这是什么，这是什么
!My pencil
！我的铅笔
[LAUGHTER]
[笑声]
.Here we go
。开始了
.SNAP] Oh]
.SNAP]哦]
NARRATOR: The second most
important rule for the artist
旁白：第二多
对艺术家来说重要的规则
at sea-- always bring
.a pencil sharpener
在海上——总是带着
.一个卷笔刀
!No-
！不-
[MUSIC PLAYING]
[音乐播放]